Shreyas Vedpathak

04 Jan 2001 | shreyasvedpathak@gmail.com | 9881898291 | 411002 Pune, India

LinkedIn ID: shreyasvedpathak | Github ID: shreyasvedpathak | Website: shreyasvedpathak.github.io

PROFILE

1+ years of expertise building and implementing deep learning algorithms using TensorFlow and PyTorch. Excited about increasing studies into artificial intelligence. I have solid technical expertise as well as an academic background in Engineering, Statistics, and Machine Learning.

EDUCATION

2018 - present Pune, India

Bachelor of Technology *MIT World Peace University* □

Current CGPA: 9.43

SKILLS

C • C++ • Python • Tensorflow • PyTorch • Scikit Learn • MySQL • MongoDB • Tableau

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nov 2021 – present

Computer Vision Intern

Ahmedabad, India

Upjao Agrotech 🛮

Contributed to the development of a scalable API powered by the GCP engine that does inference (detection, segmentation, and classification) on images containing grains and outputs indexes that are used to quantify grain quality.

Aug 2021 - present California, USA

Mentor

DeepLearning.AI □

Helped candidates enrolled in specific Coursera courses by solving their doubts,

sharing learning material, and career advices.

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 Pune, India

Data Analyst Intern

Analytics Domain 🛮

Created a web application-based analysis tool that would leverage data from public APIs. Curated course content for Machine Learning and Deep Learning topics at the beginner and intermediate levels. With the produced courses and a variety of user-side features, developed a Learning Management System.

PUBLICATIONS

Jun 2021

Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine Learning 2

UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology)

This paper aims to explore in a very uncomplicated manner, what exactly is genomics, where does high performance computing and machine learning come into picture, current applications and discuss potential future scope.

Nov 2020

PCOcare PCOS Detection and Prediction using Machine Learning

Algorithms 2

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications

Using 5 Machine Learning Algorithms, this research attempts to provide a system that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS therapy based

on an optimal and minimal set of parameters.

AWARDS

Nov 2020 **Best Paper Award** ☑

International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing

Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

PROJECTS

Oct 2020 – Nov 2020 PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML

Research Project

A system that can aid in the early identification and prediction of PCOS treatment is offered. There were several Machine Learning classifiers used. For

feature engineering, the CHI square strategy is employed.

May 2021 – present Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask

R-CNN and Res-UNet

Research Project

Image Segmentation Algorithms such as Mask Region-Based Convolutional Neural Network (Mask R-CNN), UNet, and Deep Residual U-NET successfully separated natural objects such as clouds, snow, and rivers against smoke caused

by a forest fire.

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021 Loan Management System - Flask API

Private Project

Simple loan management API made with FLASK as the backend and SQLite as the database. Token-based authentication, with Flask Blueprints for future

scaling.

Jul 2021 – Jul 2021 Hardhat Detection: Dynamically Colored Bounding Boxes

Private Project

Detecting hardhats in an image/video/live stream and offering security approval

based on the color of the hardhat.

COURSES

Machine Learning by Andrew Ng

Stanford University

TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques

deeplearning.ai

Generative Adversarial Networks Specialization

deeplearning.ai

Generative Deep Learning with TensorFlow

deeplearning.ai

REFERENCES

Dr. Kalpana Thakre, *Professor*, Sinhgad College of Engineering, Pune

kalpana sunil@yahoo.com, 9922411355

Shilpa Sonawani, Associate Professor, MIT World Peace University, Pune

shilpa.sonawani@mitwpu.edu.in, 8698955002